<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Robin Varghese</title>
    <link>http://codein.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Robin Varghese</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 15:00:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://codein.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Analytics Commons Talk</title>
      <link>http://codein.github.io/blog/top-5-tools-analytics-uses/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 14:09:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://codein.github.io/blog/top-5-tools-analytics-uses/</guid>
      <description>I gave this talk to give an overview of few tools that our department relies heavily on. This talk was part of our IS department&amp;rsquo;s commons session to give employees the chance to share their skills with examples to set and follow.
Top 5 tools Analytics uses Introduction We are hoping to give an insight into 5 tools that we rely heavily to make our life easy in Analytics department.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jupyter - Hello world</title>
      <link>http://codein.github.io/blog/hello-world-jupyter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2020 14:09:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://codein.github.io/blog/hello-world-jupyter/</guid>
      <description>4 Jupyter jupyter notebook demo link
4.a Introduction Project Jupyter is three things: a collection of standards, a community, and a set of software tools. Jupyter Notebook, one part of Jupyter, is software that creates a Jupyter notebook.
A Jupyter notebook is a document that supports mixing executable code, equations, visualizations, and narrative text. Specifically, Jupyter notebooks allow the user to bring together data, code, and prose, to tell an interactive, computational story.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>http://codein.github.io/blog/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 14:09:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://codein.github.io/blog/resume/</guid>
      <description>Robin Varghese What ever the problem, I like to be part of the solution. I thrive in an environment of uncertainty which requires constant learning. I enjoy empowering others in my knowledge space and developing software to surface information from data. Given any problem space, my hope is to be part of the solution. My aspiration is to improve health-care delivery by harnessing my skills.
Reach Me    Github LinkedIn Email Say Hello     .</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>