<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Robin Varghese</title>
    <link>https://codein.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Robin Varghese</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 15:00:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://codein.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>https://codein.github.io/blog/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2020 14:09:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codein.github.io/blog/resume/</guid>
      <description>Robin Varghese Whatever the problem, I want to be part of the solution. I enjoy developing software and empowering others in my knowledge space. I bring 10+ years of Full-Stack Developer experience and 5+ years of Leadership experience.
I thrive in an environment of uncertainty which requires constant learning.
Reach Me    Github LinkedIn Email Say Hello     . . . .    Knowledge space Tech stack             Interests Languages Tools Databases Platforms   Data Science, Analytics Python Jupyter plotly MS SQL server Amazon Web Services   Project Management, SQL git, scikit-learn AWS Athena DynamoDB Tableau   Machine learning, Cloud Computing  pandas, d3 mySQL Google Data Studio   Software, Distributed System Coffeescript Angular, bootstrap MongoDB    Kaizen, dev team building Javascript tornado, django redis    Health-care, not for profit HTML RabbitMQ postgreSQL     Experience   10+ years of experience developing software, data analytics and solving business problems with technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single-threaded vs Multi-threading vs Multi-processing in Python</title>
      <link>https://codein.github.io/blog/why-multi-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 14:09:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codein.github.io/blog/why-multi-process/</guid>
      <description>Single-threaded vs Multi-threading vs Multi-processing in Python  jupyter notebook link  We will try to run a few simulated processes to understand the performance difference between Single-threaded, Multi-threading and Multi-processing in Python.
We will learn about GIL - Alternative Python interpreters - by counting to 255 million and downloading few webpages
import concurrent.futures import requests import threading import time import math import random from multiprocessing import Pool # Reference and Credits # https://realpython.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>USPS API Proof of Concept</title>
      <link>https://codein.github.io/blog/usps-api-proof-of-concept/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 14:09:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codein.github.io/blog/usps-api-proof-of-concept/</guid>
      <description>USPS API Proof of Concept  jupyter notebook link  I was hoping to demostrate how one can pull tracking information from USPS API endpoint for a given tracking ID.
Acknowledgements  all documentation was available on this webpage https://www.usps.com/business/web-tools-apis/track-and-confirm-api.htm#_Toc41911504  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro to SQL with 5000 movies</title>
      <link>https://codein.github.io/blog/intro-to-sql/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 14:09:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codein.github.io/blog/intro-to-sql/</guid>
      <description>Intro to SQL with 5000 movies  jupyter notebook link  This notebook is a part of a talk i have been giving to introduce people to SQL. Only pre-requisite to attend this talk is some general curiosity.
Acknowledgements This dataset was generated from The Movie Database API. This product uses the TMDb API but is not endorsed or certified by TMDb. We used the dataset published on kaggle that includes 5000 movies</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL upsert loader</title>
      <link>https://codein.github.io/blog/sql-upsert-loader/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 14:09:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codein.github.io/blog/sql-upsert-loader/</guid>
      <description>Overview of SQL upsert loader   jupyter notebook link
  source code
  I hope to present a Proof Of Concept version of a multiprocessed data loader that I use extensively in my data integration pipelines.
Couple of problems that it is attempting to address are
 Ability to operate on any update flat file associated with a SQL table, with minor configuration. Ability to perform upsert operations on datasets without a primary key column.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analytics Commons Talk</title>
      <link>https://codein.github.io/blog/top-5-tools-analytics-uses/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 14:09:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codein.github.io/blog/top-5-tools-analytics-uses/</guid>
      <description>I gave this talk to give an overview of few tools that our department relies heavily on. This talk was part of our IS department&amp;rsquo;s commons session to give employees the chance to share their skills with examples to set and follow.
Top 5 tools Analytics uses Introduction We are hoping to give an insight into 5 tools that we rely heavily to make our life easy in Analytics department.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jupyter - Hello world</title>
      <link>https://codein.github.io/blog/hello-world-jupyter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2020 14:09:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codein.github.io/blog/hello-world-jupyter/</guid>
      <description>4 Jupyter jupyter notebook demo link
4.a Introduction Project Jupyter is three things: a collection of standards, a community, and a set of software tools. Jupyter Notebook, one part of Jupyter, is software that creates a Jupyter notebook.
A Jupyter notebook is a document that supports mixing executable code, equations, visualizations, and narrative text. Specifically, Jupyter notebooks allow the user to bring together data, code, and prose, to tell an interactive, computational story.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maestro Job Engine Architecture</title>
      <link>https://codein.github.io/blog/maestro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codein.github.io/blog/maestro/</guid>
      <description>Maestro Job Engine Architecture +---------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------+ | | | | | Maestro Job Engine Architecture | | | | | | | | +---------------------------+ | | | | | | | execute 1 | | | | | | | +---------------------------+ | | | | +---------------------------+ +------+----------+--------+--------------------------------------+-------------+ | | | | push logs to Database | date | job_name | status | tags | debug_data | | | | logging 2 | +---------------------&amp;gt; +-------------------------------------------------------------------------------+ | | | | | | | | | | | | +---------------------------+ | | | | #frequency #type #priority #author | | | | | | | | examples | | | | +---------------------------+ | | | | #daily #etl #critical #robin | | | | | | analyze logs | | | | #weekly #test #minor #bart | | | | | monitoring 3 | &amp;lt;---------------------+ | | | | #hourly #API #monitoring #dev #paul | | | | | | | | | | | | | | +----------+----------------+ +------+----------+--------+--------------------------------------+-------------+ | | | | | | | | | | | | notification | | | | | v | | +----------+----------------+ | | | | | | | Errors | | | | critical: 0 | | | | minor: 1 | | | | warning: 12 | | | | test: 1 | | | | dev: 5 | | | | success: 150 | | | | | | | +---------------------------+ | | | | | | | +---------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------+ </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://codein.github.io/blog/ha/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codein.github.io/blog/ha/</guid>
      <description>ha (刃, edge) - the tempered cutting edge of a katana.
Scorecard metrics measurement OLAP cube sits Scorecard critical performance information on a single screen so users can monitor results in a glance.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>